SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer specializing in Ruby on Rails, Javascript, and SQL. I really enjoy creating software, especially on the backend working with databases and APIs. I went to school for engineering, but early in my career I caught the programming bug and left to complete an apprenticeship at a software company. Since then I have enjoyed delivering quality web and mobile applications of various kinds, including cofounding a startup of which I am very proud.

SKILLS

- Ruby, JavaScript, Go, Elasticsearch
- Ruby on Rails, Node.js, React
- SQL and NoSQL of all types
- · HTML, CSS, jQuery
- React Native, Cordova, Ionic

- TDD, BDD
- REST API design
- Relational database design
- Server management (Heroku, AWS)
- Agile/Scrum methodology

EXPERIENCE

Cofounder, Lead Software Engineer

Jan 2015 to Present

Insurance Skout, Inc.

Primarily San Francisco, Denver, New York

- Cofounded a software company in the health insurance space.
- Created a SaaS platform for insurance agencies/brokers with ~80 paying customers.
- Designed and built Ruby on Rails app, PostgreSQL db, and Go/Elasticsearch microservices.
- Managed a team of 4 using Agile/Scrum methodology.

Software Engineer

Jan 2015 to Present

Freelance

Primarily San Francisco, Denver, New York

- Created various web and mobile applications as part of a small contractor team.
- Designated as the primary backend engineer specializing in databases and APIs.
- Worked with a fully remote team while traveling and experiencing many places.

Software Engineer

Jan 2014 to Jan 2015

West Arete (Custom Software)

State College, PA

- Created software primarily using Ruby on Rails with an emphasis on TDD.
- Promoted from an apprenticeship into a full time salaried role.
- Worked with high profile clients such as Pennsylvania State University and the DoD.

Junior Developer

Jan 2013 to Jan 2014

Xsalta (Web Marketing)

State College, PA

- Worked as a part time developer while attending college for engineering.
- Gained a strong understanding of web programming basics.
- Contributed to many static websites (html/css/jQuery).

EDUCATION

West Arete (Custom Software) Pennsylvania State University

Ruby on Rails Apprenticeship, 2014 Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, 2009-2013